KAYLA RAMIREZ

SENIOR SOFTWARE ANALYST

361.834.2949



ram.kayla@gmail.com



Austin, Texas



EDUCATION

BACHELOR'S DEGREE, COMPUTATIONAL BIOLOGY

University of Texas | Austin, TX Summer 2014

SKILLS

Python

Django

Natural

HTML/CSS

Oracle

JavaScript

Splunk

Mulesoft

Project Management

Jira/Jira Service Desk

UX/UI Design

Customer Service

INTERESTS

Coach for The University of Texas Ultimate Team 08.2017 - Present

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Senior Software Analyst and Developer with nearly 5 years of experience working with clients and stakeholders to analyze business needs and to create innovative applications to meet those ends. In particular, assessing third party products as IT solutions, building proof of concepts and managing integration and training.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer/Analyst

University of Texas – Austin | 06.2019 – Present

- Led multiple services by functioning as the primary resource for service support and leadership i.e. Jira Service Desk, MyUT, Mulesoft and Kuali Build.
- Assessed vendor products, built proof of concepts, created APIs for integration and project managed implementation and assisted with training and documentation.
- Analyzed data needs and designed database structures for efficient data storage and retrieval.
- As Training Education Coordinator, coordinated the AIS internal training program for new developers.

Software Developer/Analyst

University of Texas - Austin | 09.2015 - 08.2017

- Designed and implemented new features and enhancements to The University of Texas Interactive Degree Audit System.
- Built relationships with clients and worked with stakeholders to analyze business processes and elicit business requirements.
- Created mock-ups and developed web applications for staff that were previously working with mainframe interfaces.
- Tested and demoed final product to staff, as well as created training documentation.

Lead Community Assistant

The Quarters on Campus | 08.2012 - 07.2014

- Assisted leasing office staff with clerical work and greeted and assisted residents with any problems they may have with their apartment.
- Supervised fellow community assistants and acted as a liaison between the community assistants and leasing manager
- Helped develop and host marketing events for residents and potential residents to promote community involvement and interest.